Register of the Alfred M. Lilienthal papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- SPEECHES AND WRITINGS, 1938-1995 (Boxes 31-68, 152-153)
  - "Toward a New Middle East Policy," 21 November 1983. Typescript article sent to the New York Times op-ed editor, written by AML and Kenneth Love (Box-folder 67: 6)
  - Letter to the editor, Sun (Lowell, Mass.), (date written). Typescript, 6 December 1983 (Box-folder 67: 7)
  - "What Kind of Israel?" Middle East International, Printed copy, 27 January 1984. (Box-folder 67: 8)
  - Letter to the editor, Time, (date written). Typescript, 2 March 1984 (Box-folder 67: 9)
  - "Does It Serve the United States' Own National Interest to Be the Arsenal and Treasury of Israel?" Speech, University of Delaware, Newark, Delaware. Press release, announcement, and clipping, 12 April 1984. (Box-folder 67: 10)
  - "Politics and Religion in the Middle East," Speech, 14th Annual National Convention of American Atheists, Lexington, Kentucky. Printed copy, typescript, press release, clipping, and correspondence, 21 April 1984. (Box-folder 67: 11)
  - "Zionism: The Occupying Power," Paper, International Progress Organization symposium, Vienna, Austria. Printed copy, typescript, clipping, and correspondence, 2-4 May 1984. (Box-folder 68: 1)
  - Interview by Kathy Kakish, Jerusalem Star, Printed copy, 26 July 1984. (Box-folder 68: 2)
  - "The Gulf War, the Palestinian Question, and Zionism," Speech, International Conference on the Impact of the Gulf War on World Peace and Security, Baghdad, Iraq. Typescript, handwritten notes, and clipping. Includes speeches by other participants, 8-10 July 1984. (Box-folder 68: 3)
  - Remarks, Sabra and Shatila Memorial Meeting, Commemoration Program, Organizational Coalition, Hotel Washington, Washington, D.C., Typescript, 15 September 1984. (Box-folder 68: 4)
  - Remarks, Sabra and Shatila Memorial Meeting, Commemoration Program, Holy Land Committee, Hotel Washington, Washington, D.C., Typescript, 18 September 1984. (Box-folder 68: 5)
  - "To the Victor Belongs ..." Typescript op-ed sent to various newspapers and individuals, 8 November 1984. (Box-folder 68: 6)
  - Letter to the editor, American Sunbeam, Printed and typescript copies, 19 November 1984. (Box-folder 68: 7)
  - "Lebanon: What a Stinking, Horrible Mess," National Educator, Printed copy, December 1984. (Box-folder 68: 8)
  - "Depoliticize the Middle East Conflict through Bi-Partisanship or Face Nuclear War," Speech, University of Wisconsin, Madison, Wisconsin. Press release and clipping, 6 December 1984. (Box-folder 68: 9)
  - "Everyone Culpable for Sabra-Shatila Massacres," Jerusalem Palestinian Weekly, Printed copy, 28 December 1984. (Box-folder 68: 10)
  - "The Zionist Lobby in the United States," March 1985. Handwritten draft of article intended for Signal Magazine (Box-folder 68: 11)
  - Letter to the editor, New York, week ending Printed and typescript copies, 29 April 1985. (Box-folder 68: 12)
  - "The Media and American Foreign Policy in the Middle East," 2 May 1985. Speech, Georgetown University, Washington, D.C. Handwritten notes and letter from Nadia Sa'd (Box-folder 68: 13)
  - Interview by Grace Halsell, Arab News Features, Printed copy, 8 May 1985. (Box-folder 68: 14)
  - "U.S. Foreign Policy in the Middle East: In Whose Interest?" Paper, Freedoms Foundation at Valley Forge seminar, Valley Forge, Pennsylvania, 2-7 June 1985. Typescript and correspondence, 4 June 1985. (Box-folder 68: 15)
  - Press conference, National Press Club, Washington, D.C., Typescript, press release, and clipping, 12 June 1985. (Box-folder 68: 16)
  - Interview by Abdul Salem Y. Massarueh, Daily Gulf Times, Printed copy, 16 June 1985. (Box-folder 68: 17)
  - "Pro-Israel Policy Feeds Violence," USA Today, 3 July 1985. Printed copy and reprint from the Congressional Record of, 7 November 1985 (Box-folder 68: 18)
  - Interview by Abdul Salem Y. Massarueh, Palestine, Printed copy, 15 July-1 August 1985. (Box-folder 68: 19)
  - Interview by Abdul Salem Y. Massarueh, Arabia, Printed copy, September 1985. (Box-folder 68: 20)
  - Remarks, Authors' Roundtable, American-Arab Anti-Discrimination Committee Annual Convention, Washington Hilton, Washington, D.C., Correspondence, 8 September 1985. (Box-folder 68: 21)
  - "What Price Middle East Peace?" Speech, Cornell Club of Washington, Washington, D.C. Typescript, typescript introduction by Robert F. McKinless, and correspondence, 10 September 1985. (Box-folder 68: 22)
  - "Count Folke Bernadotte: A Man to Remember," Sermon, Communion Service on the 37th Anniversary of Count Folke Bernadotte's Assassination in Jerusalem, University of Delaware, Newark, Delaware. Typescript, 17 September 1985. (Box-folder 68: 23)
  - Letter to the editor, New York Times, (date written). Typescript, 14 October 1985 (Box-folder 68: 24)
  - "Middle East Terror: The Double Standard," Phi Beta Kappa Association of Washington, D.C. Printed and typescript copies, and correspondence, 16 October 1985. (Box-folder 68: 25)
  - Remarks, International Progress Organization colloquium on "Democracy in international relations," Plaza Hotel, New York City, Typescript and correspondence, 31 October 1985. (Box-folder 68: 26)
  - Letter to the editor, New York Times, (date written). Typescript, 11 November 1985 (Box-folder 68: 27)
  - Letter to the editor, Arizona Daily Star, (date written; appeared sometime in December 1985). Typescript, 27 November 1985 (Box-folder 68: 28)
  - Letter to the editor, The Wall Street Journal, Printed copy, 10 December 1985. (Box-folder 68: 29)
  - "The Middle East: Is there a Solution?" 1986. Printed copy of a fictive interview by Juraj Racz based on the lectures, interviews, press conferences, and articles that appeared or were used in the Czechoslovak mass media during and after his visit to Prague, Czechoslovakia, Includes clippings from the Czech press, 27-30 May 1985. (Box-folder 68: 30)
  - Open letter to President Ronald Reagan, (not released). Typescript, 24 January 1986 (Box-folder 68: 31)
  - "Delivering for Israel," Middle East International, Printed and typescript copies, 7 March 1986. (Box-folder 68: 32)
  - "Middle East Terror: The Double Standard," Speech, University of Western Ontario, London, Ontario, Canada. Clippings and correspondence with Edward C. Corrigan, as well as his report on AML's visit to London, 21 March 1986. (Box-folder 68: 33)
  - "Middle East Terror: The Double Standard," Speech, University of Toronto, Toronto, Canada. Clippings, 22 March 1986. (Box-folder 68: 34)
  - Appearance, Rod MacDonald talk show, CFCF Radio, Montreal, Canada, Clipping, 25-26 March 1986. (Box-folder 68: 35)
  - "Middle East Terror: The Double Standard," Speech, McGill University, Montreal, Canada. Introduction of AML, 26 March 1986. (Box-folder 68: 36)
  - Speech, Parliamentary Middle East Group, Ottawa, Canada, Clipping, April 1986. (Box-folder 68: 37)
  - "I Dare Speak Out," Typescript, 7 April 1986. (Box-folder 152: 52)
  - Teach-in on the United States' bombing of Libya, Cornell University, Ithaca, New York, Clipping, 8 May 1986. (Box-folder 68: 38)
  - Letter to the editor, Washington Post, Printed copy and typescript draft, 14 May 1986. (Box-folder 68: 39)
  - Letter to the editor, International Herald Tribune, Printed copy, 22 May 1986. (Box-folder 68: 40)
  - Letter to the editor, Atlanta Constitution, (date written). Typescript. Includes correspondence with T. J. Campbell, 28 May 1986 (Box-folder 68: 41)
  - Statement on the elections of Kurt Waldheim, Typescript, 10 June 1986. (Box-folder 152: 53)
  - "Semite and Anti-Semite: A Confusion Stifling American Freedom," Washington Report on Middle East Affairs, Printed copy, 14 July 1986. (Box-folder 152: 28)
  - Remarks, Press conference on Israeli attack on U.S.S. Liberty, Capitol Hill Club, Washington, D.C., Typescript and newspaper article reproducing AML's letter to Rep. Connie Mack, 1986 November 28, 1 October 1986. (Box-folder 68: 42)
  - Letter to the editor, Washington Jewish Week, Printed copy, 13 November 1986. (Box-folder 68: 43)
  - Letter to the editor, Washington Post, (date written). Typescript, 22 November 1986 (Box-folder 68: 44)
  - Letter to the editor, New York Times, (date written). Typescript, 26 November 1986 (Box-folder 68: 45)
  - "Semite and Anti-Semite: A Confusion Stifling American Freedom," Typescript, 1987. (Box-folder 68: 46)
  - Comments, Forum on Terrorism, 1987 Student Symposium on International Terrorism, Millsaps College, Jackson, Mississippi, Typescript and clipping, 20-21 January 1987. (Box-folder 68: 47)
  - Letter to the editor, Tikkun, Printed copy, September/October 1987. (Box-folder 68: 48)
  - Message read by John Collins at the memorial service for Leonard S. Schlafer, San Juan, Puerto Rico, Typescript, 7 November 1987. (Box-folder 68: 49)
  - "What Price Middle East Peace?" Speech, George Washington University, Washington, D.C. Typescript and invitation, 26 January 1988. (Box-folder 152: 1)
  - "What Price Middle East Peace?" Speech, University of Tennessee, Knoxville, Tennessee. Typescript, press release, and announcement, 1 February 1988. (Box-folder 152: 2)
  - Press release, Typescript, 24 February 1988. (Box-folder 152: 3)
  - Statement after a 10-day stay in Jerusalem, Typescript, March 1988. (Box-folder 152: 4)
  - Speech, Bridgewater College, Virginia, Press release, 17 March 1988. (Box-folder 152: 5)
  - Speech, Concordia University, Montreal, Canada, Clippings, 23 March 1988. (Box-folder 152: 6)
  - Interview, Realites, Printed copy, 26 March 1988. (Box-folder 152: 7)
  - "Middle East Terror: The Double Standard," Speech, University of Windsor, Windsor, Ontario, Canada. Clipping, 26 March 1988. (Box-folder 152: 8)
  - Speech, Canadian Arab Society of London, London, Ontario, Canada, Correspondence with Omar Jabara and clippings, 27 March 1988. (Box-folder 152: 9)
  - Letter to the editor, Christian Science Monitor, Printed copy, 7 April 1988. (Box-folder 152: 10)
  - Letter to the editor, Stanford Daily, Printed copy, 12 May 1988. (Box-folder 152: 11)
  - Letter to the editor, London Free Press, 18 May 1988. Printed copy. Includes article by Jack Briglia, London Free Press, 20 April 1988 (Box-folder 152: 12)
  - "All the News that's Fit to Slant," Typescript, 5 July 1988. (Box-folder 153: 15)
  - Notes, Typescript, 16-17 July 1988. (Box-folder 152: 54)
  - "Doing Anything Better Than You Can," Washington Report on Middle East Affairs, Printed copy, September 1988. (Box-folder 152: 13)
  - "Witness to History: New York, 1947 - Tunis, 1988," Washington Report on Middle East Affairs, Printed copy, October 1988. (Box-folder 152: 14)
  - Letter to the editor, Christian Science Monitor, 3 October 1988. Printed copy. Includes an article by George D. Moffett III, Christian Science Monitor, 14 September 1988 (Box-folder 152: 15)
  - Open letter to Yasir Arafat, 2 November 1988. Typescript and printed copy, Washington Report on Middle East Affairs (Box-folder 152: 16)
  - "A State Is Born: Obstacles That Lie Ahead," The Return, Printed copy, December 1988. (Box-folder 152: 17)
  - Speech, Model International Peace Conference on the Middle East, Prague, Czechoslovakia, Typescript and proceedings, 6 December 1988. (Box-folder 152: 18)
  - Proposed resolution sponsored by AML and Hans Koechler, Typescript, 8 December 1988. (Box-folder 152: 29)
  - "The U.S. Media and the PLO: Will Things Ever Change?," Washington Report on Middle East Affairs, Printed copy. Includes mimeographed copy for the March 1989 newsletter of Americans for Better Government, February 1989. (Box-folder 152: 19)
  - "Eyewitness to History: What Price Middle East Peace?" Speech, Virginia. Typescript, April 1989. (Box-folder 152: 55)
  - "Eyewitness to History: What Price Middle East Peace?" Speech, Rotary Club of Washington, D.C. Typescript, correspondence, and announcement, 14 June 1989. (Box-folder 152: 20)
  - Statement, Press Conference, Prague, Czechoslovakia, Typescript, 6 July 1989. (Box-folder 152: 30)
  - Contribution, Forum, Guild Hall, East Hampton, New York, Clipping, 16 August 1989. (Box-folder 152: 21)
  - Speech, Colorado State University, Fort Collins, Colorado, Press release, flyer, and clippings, 6 November 1989. (Box-folder 152: 22)
  - "On Anti-Semitism and Self-Censorship," Return, Printed copy, January 1990. (Box-folder 152: 31)
  - Letter to the editor, intended for the Washington Post, written 30 November 1989, but published in Washington Report, Printed copy, February 1990. (Box-folder 152: 32)
  - "Why the Palestinians Lose Out in the U.S.," Middle East International, Printed copy, 16 February 1990. (Box-folder 152: 33)
  - "After the Gulf War: What Price Middle East Peace?" Speech, University United Methodist Student Center, Gainesville, Florida. Flyer, press release, and clipping, 8 April 1991. (Box-folder 152: 37)
  - "What Price the Gulf War?" Speech, University of Florida, Gainesville, Florida. Flyer, 10 April 1991. (Box-folder 152: 38)
  - Letter to the editor, Washington Post, (date written). Typescript, 6 July 1991 (Box-folder 152: 39)
  - "The Grand Illusion of Jewish Ethnicity," Middle East Policy, Printed copy, 1992. (Box-folder 153: 1)
  - "What Price Middle East Peace," Speech, University Club, Washington, D.C. Printed copy, 23 April 1992. (Box-folder 153: 2)
  - "U.S. Middle East Policy: What It Has Been and What It Ought to Be," Testimony before the Platform Committee of the 1992 Republican National Convention, Washington, D.C. Press release, typescript, and printed excerpts, 15 June 1992. (Box-folder 153: 3)
  - Speech, Daughters of the American Revolution, Nantucket, Massachusetts, Clipping, 27 August 1992. (Box-folder 153: 4)
  - "Using Israel to Pander for the Jewish Vote Hasn't Changed Since 1948," Washington Report on Middle East Affairs, Printed copy, August-September 1992. (Box-folder 153: 5)
  - Letter to the editor, Stanford Daily, printed copy, 23 November 1992. (Box-folder 153: 6)
  - "What Price Middle East Peace?" Speech, National Association of Arab Americans, Los Angeles, California. Program, tributes read at the dinner honoring AML, printed copy, and clipping, 5 December 1992. (Box-folder 153: 7)
  - "Shielding Israel From Sanctions Recalls Failed Policies of Past," Washington Report on Middle East Affairs, Printed copy, March 1993. (Box-folder 153: 8)
  - "Israel's Flag Is Not Mine," 3 May 1993. Interview by Ghassan Bishara, Al-Fajr. Printed copy (Box-folder 153: 9)
  - "The Changing Role of B'nai B'rith's Anti-Defamation League," Washington Report on Middle East Affairs, Printed copy, June 1993. (Box-folder 153: 10)
  - "Lilienthal Remarks at 80th Birthday Commemoration," Remarks, The University Club, Washington, D.C. Typescript, 18 December 1993. (Box-folder 153: 13)
  - This I Do Believe! Selections from the Writings, Lectures and Statements of Dr. Alfred M. Lilienthal, Printed copy, 18 December 1993. (Box-folder 153: 14)
  - Statement upon returning from Beirut and Amman, Typescript, 19 May 1994. (Box-folder 153: 20)
  - "What Price Middle East Peace?" Speech, Freedom Party of Austria, Vienna, Austria. Typescript, 23 June 1994. (Box-folder 153: 21)
  - "The Middle East: Will There Really Be Peace?" Speech, University Club, Washington, D.C. Typescript and printed copy, 13 October 1994. (Box-folder 153: 22)
  - "The Tragedy of Ma'alot Casts a Shadow on Peace Negotiations," Washington Report on Middle East Affairs, Printed copy, November/December 1994. (Box-folder 153: 23)
  - "The King and I: Eyewitness to History," Washington Report on Middle East Affairs, Printed copy, March 1995. (Box-folder 153: 24)
  - "J. William Fulbright: A Giant Passes," Washington Report on Middle East Affairs, Includes letter to the editor. Printed copy, April-May 1995. (Box-folder 153: 25)
  - Letter to the editor, Washington Report on Middle East Affairs, Reproduces a letter to Bill Clinton, 20 April 1995, and a letter from John F. Kennedy to AML, 30 September 1960. Printed copy, June 1995. (Box-folder 153: 26)
- SUBJECT FILE, 1942-1989 (Boxes 69-95, 153)
  Conference proceedings, correspondence, memoranda, notes, reports, studies, clippings, and other printed matter, arranged alphabetically by subject.
  - Abend, Martin (Box-folder 69: 1)
  - Abourezk, James (Box-folder 69: 2)
  - Acheson, Dean (Box-folder 69: 3)
  - Action Committee on American-Arab Relations (Box-folder 69: 4)
  - Adenauer, Konrad (Box-folder 69: 5)
  - Affirmative action (Box-folder 69: 6)
  - Africa, North (Box-folder 69: 7)
  - Agnew, Spiro (Box-folder 69: 8)
  - Alexander, Holmes (Box-folder 69: 9)
  - Alia Report (Box-folder 69: 10)
  - Allah, Fadl (Box-folder 69: 11)
  - American Aid for Arab Refugees (Box-folder 69: 12)
  - American Arab Society (Box-folder 69: 13)
  - American Christians for Justice in Palestine (Box-folder 69: 14)
  - American Committee for Justice in the Middle East (Box-folder 69: 15)
  - American Council for Judaism. See also Israel, Constitution and United Nations, Resolutions, (Partition plan), 1947 (Box-folder 69: 16)
  - American Council on the Middle East (Box-folder 69: 17)
  - American Egyptian Society (Box-folder 69: 18)
  - American Friends Service Committee (Box-folder 69: 19)
  - American Friends of Lebanon (Box-folder 69: 20)
  - American Friends of Palestinians (Box-folder 69: 21)
  - American Friends of the Middle East. See also CORRESPONDENCE, Eddy, William
    - General (Box-folder 69: 22)
    - Committee for Reorganization (Box-folder 69: 23)
  - American-Israel Chamber of Commerce and Industry (Box-folder 69: 24)
  - American Israel Public Affairs Committee (Box-folder 69: 25)
  - American Jewish Alternatives to Zionism (Box-folder 69: 26)
  - American Middle East Council (Box-folder 69: 27)
  - American Middle East Rehabilitation. See also American Near East Refugee Aid (Box-folder 69: 28)
  - American Palestine Committee. See Dacey, Norman
  - American Near East Refugee Aid (Box-folder 70: 1)
  - American University in Cairo - Board of Trustees. See SPEECHES AND WRITINGS, for list of members, 11 April 1979
  - American University of Beirut (Box-folder 70: 2)
  - Americans for Justice in the Middle East (Box-folder 70: 3)
  - Americans for Middle East Understanding (Box-folder 70: 4)
  - Anglo-American Committee of Inquiry. Report, April 20, 1946 (Box-folder 70: 5)
  - Anti-Defamation League of B'nai B'rith. See also CORRESPONDENCE, Miller, Sigmund (Box-folder 70: 6)
  - Anti-semitism
    - General (Box-folder 70: 7)
    - Anti-anti-semitism (Box-folder 70: 8)
  - Arab American Dialogue Committee (Box-folder 70: 9)
  - Arab American organizations (Box-folder 70: 10)
  - Arab boycott. See also CORRESPONDENCE, Mahgoub, M. M.; AMERICAN-ARAB ASSOCIATION FOR COMMERCE AND INDUSTRY, Subject file, Ouster of AML
    - General (Box-folder 70: 11)
    - General (Box-folder 71: 1-2)
    - AML's letters of to David Steinberg (in answer to his column of 15 April 1962 in the New York Herald Tribune) and of to Arthur Ochs Sulzberger, New York Times, 25 April 1962 13 December 1963 (Box-folder 71: 3)
    - Mancroft case (Box-folder 71: 4)
    - Media coverage (Box-folder 71: 5)
    - National Association of Arab Americans Conference, Washington, D.C., Includes writings by AML, 18 November 1976. (Box-folder 71: 6)
  - Arab-British Centre (Box-folder 71: 7)
  - Arab investments in the United States (Box-folder 71: 8)
  - Arab-Israeli Conflict
    - General (Box-folder 71: 9)
    - Suleiman, Michael W., "Development of World Opinion on the Question of Palestine,", n.d. (Box-folder 71: 10)
    - 1956 (Box-folder 71: 11)
    - 1967 (Box-folder 72: 1-2)
    - 1973 (Box-folder 72: 3)
  - Arab propaganda in the United States (Box-folder 72: 4)
  - Arabs
    - General (Box-folder 72: 5)
    - Israel (Box-folder 72: 6)
    - United States (Box-folder 72: 7)
  - Arafat, Yasir. See also Vatican (Box-folder 72: 8)
  - Australian Broadcasting Company (re investigation of Radio Station 3CR) (Box-folder 72: 9)
  - Austria (Box-folder 72: 10)
  - Bahrain (Box-folder 73: 1)
  - Balfour Declaration (Box-folder 73: 2)
  - Begin, Menachem. See also CORRESPONDENCE, American Council for Judaism and Anderson, Francis W.; SPEECHES AND WRITINGS, 5 August 1970 (Box-folder 73: 3)
  - Bellow, Saul (Box-folder 73: 4)
  - Bench, Nachman (Box-folder 73: 5)
  - Berlin, Michael. See CORRESPONDENCE, Columbia School of Journalism
  - Bernadotte, Folke (Box-folder 73: 6)
  - Booth, John Nicholls (Box-folder 73: 7)
  - Brando, Marlon (Box-folder 73: 8)
  - BREIRA (A Project of Concern in Diaspora-Israel Relations). See also Middle East, Peace plans (Box-folder 73: 9)
  - British-American Committee on the Middle East (Box-folder 73: 10)
  - British Anti-Zionist Organization (Box-folder 73: 11)
  - Broadcast Interview Connection (Box-folder 73: 12)
  - Brown, George (Box-folder 73: 13)
  - Bryen, Steve (Box-folder 73: 14)
  - Burleson, Omar (Box-folder 73: 15)
  - Bush, George (Box-folder 73: 16)
  - CAMERA (Committee for Accuracy in Middle East Reporting in America) (Box-folder 73: 17)
  - Camp David accords, See Middle East, Peace Treaty of March 26, 1979, September 1978.
  - Canada (Box-folder 73: 18)
  - Carleton, Alford (Box-folder 73: 19)
  - Carnegie Endowment (Box-folder 73: 20)
  - Carter, Billy (Box-folder 73: 21)
  - Carter, Jimmy (Box-folder 73: 22)
  - Catholics (Box-folder 73: 23)
  - Center for Middle East Policy (Box-folder 73: 24)
  - Chile (Box-folder 73: 25)
  - Chomsky, Noam (Box-folder 73: 26)
  - Christian fundamentalists (Box-folder 73: 27)
  - Christians (Box-folder 73: 28)
  - Clark, Ed (Box-folder 74: 1)
  - Clifford, Clark. See also CORRESPONDENCE, Nierengarten, William J. (Box-folder 74: 2)
  - Collins, John (Box-folder 74: 3)
  - Committee to Save the Middle East from Communism (Box-folder 74: 4)
  - Common Cause (Box-folder 74: 5)
  - Coordination Committee of Jewish Intellectuals and Organizations for Peace and Justice in the Middle East (Box-folder 74: 6)
  - Cornell University (Box-folder 153: 11)
  - Council on Islamic Affairs (Box-folder 74: 7)
  - Curry, William A. (Box-folder 74: 8)
  - D'Amato, Al (Box-folder 74: 9)
  - Dacey, Norman (Box-folder 74: 10)
  - Dayan, Moshe (Box-folder 74: 11)
  - DeHaan Report (Box-folder 74: 12)
  - Deir Yassin (Box-folder 74: 13)
  - Denton, Charles R. (Box-folder 74: 14)
  - Dickson, Fagan (Box-folder 74: 15)
  - Dulles, John Foster (Box-folder 74: 16)
  - Eban, Abba (Box-folder 74: 17)
  - Economic Club of New York (Box-folder 74: 18)
  - Egypt. See also Israel (Box-folder 75: 1)
  - Eichmann trial (Box-folder 75: 2)
  - Einstein, Albert (Box-folder 75: 3)
  - Eisenhower, Dwight D. See also SPEECHES AND WRITINGS, 2 April 1957 (Box-folder 75: 4)
  - Elmessiri, A. (Box-folder 75: 5)
  - Entebbe raid (Box-folder 75: 6)
  - Erhard, Ludwig (Box-folder 75: 7)
  - Esmail, Sami (Box-folder 75: 8)
  - European Coordinating Committee of Friendship Societies with the Arab World (Box-folder 75: 9)
  - Exodus (Leon Uris) (Box-folder 75: 10)
  - Faisal, King of Saudi Arabia (Box-folder 75: 11)
  - Falwell, Jerry (Box-folder 75: 12)
  - Fath (Organization) (Box-folder 75: 13)
  - Fedayeen (Popular Democratic Front for the Liberation of Palestine) (Box-folder 75: 14)
  - Federal Communications Commission (Box-folder 75: 15)
  - Federated Americans against Israeli Racism (Box-folder 75: 16)
  - Federated Organizations on American-Arab Relations (Box-folder 75: 17)
  - Federation Movement in America (One People, One Destiny) (Box-folder 75: 18)
  - First Voters League (Box-folder 75: 19)
  - "Flashpoint: Israel and the Palestinians" (TV program) (Box-folder 75: 20)
  - Ford, Gerald R. (Box-folder 75: 21)
  - Forrest, A. C. (Box-folder 75: 22)
  - Forrestal, James Vincent (Box-folder 75: 23)
  - Foundation for Education on the Middle East (Box-folder 75: 24)
  - France (Box-folder 75: 25)
  - Fulbright, J. William (Box-folder 75: 26)
  - Gaulle, Charles de (Box-folder 76: 1)